The President's Cake is a drama film directed by Hasan Hadi.
In 1990s Iraq, it's 'draw day', when schools select students for the honour of bringing items
to their mandatory local celebrations of President Saddam Hussein's birthday.
Nine-year-old Lamia lives in the historic marshes
with her spirited grandmother, Bibi.
Before school, Bibi teaches Lamia clever tricks to
avoid being chosen for the baking duties.
However, when Musa, the authoritative teacher, calls Lamia's name for the most
challenging task–the birthday cake–she has no choice but to accept.
Refusing could mean imprisonment or even death.
Lamia, played by Banin Ahmad Nayef.
Saeed, played by Sajad Mohamad Qasem.
Bibi, played by Waheed Thabet Khreibat.
Jasim, played by Rahim AlHaj.
Muthanna, played by Muthanna Malaghi.
Musa, played by Ahmad Qasem Saywan.
The President's Cake (Arabic: مملكة القصب) is a 2025 drama
film written and directed by Hasan Hadi.
It stars Baneen Ahmad Nayyef, Sajad Mohamad Qasem,
Waheed Thabet Khreibat and Rahim AlHaj.
The film had its world premiere at the Directors' Fortnight section of the 2025 Cannes Film
Festival on May 16, 2025, where it won the section's Audience Award and the Caméra d'Or.
It was selected as the Iraqi entry for Best International Feature Film at
the 98th Academy Awards, making the December shortlist.
It is scheduled to be released in the United States by
Sony Pictures Classics on February 6, 2026.
The film explores themes of dictatorship, birthday cake,
police arrest, counterfeit money, 1990s.
The tone is emotional.